gowalla.com 2011-12-24

# Privacy | Gowalla

Gowalla, Inc. (“Gowalla,” “we,” or “us”), knows that you care how information about you is used and shared. This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by Gowalla when you use the Gowalla Service, how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this policy are defined in our Terms of Use. We expect that Users will use Gowalla for harmless and fun social purposes. Please note, though, that by its nature, your location information is subject to abuse, misuse, and over-monitoring by others including, perhaps, by your friends, family, or acquaintances. Please manage your own mobile and profile privacy preferences on the Service, on an ongoing basis, accordingly. 

##  Using the Gowalla Mobile Service 

In order to use the mobile features of the Gowalla Service, you must consent to: (a) the use of your phone’s location to provide Gowalla to you, including the display and disclosure of that location information to your Gowalla friends and within your geo-tagged messages and content; (b) receive text messages; and (c) pay carrier data, messaging, and other fees resulting from Gowalla usage. Data and messaging (including SMS text messages) plans are required to use the mobile features of the Gowalla Service. Standard data and messaging charges, fees, and taxes from your carrier apply. 

##  Information We Collect 

  1. **User-Provided Information:** You provide us information about yourself, such as your name, e-mail address, mobile phone number and carrier, etc., if you register for a Member account with the Service. When using the Service, you may also provide certain other personal information and content, such as locations and activities, which will be publicly displayed to other Users and on third-party sites and services in accordance with your privacy and opt-in settings. To provide the mobile features of the Service, we derive location information from your wireless carrier, certain third-party service providers, or directly from the mobile device that you used to register with Gowalla. This location tracking of your mobile device occurs only when the Gowalla mobile application is actively open and running. 
  2. **Location Information:** To provide Gowalla, we collect, maintain, use, and display your personal data and the geographic location of your mobile device (we call this location fix of your mobile device “location information”). 
  3. **Cookies Information:** When you visit Gowalla.com, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets Gowalla help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may also convey anonymous information about how you browse the Service to us. A cookie does not collect personal information about you. Gowalla uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. 
  4. **Log File Information:** Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. When you register with or view our site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information. 
  5. **Clear Gifs Information:** When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our users anonymously. No personally identifiable information from your Gowalla account is collected using these clear gifs. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and make Gowalla better for our users. 

##  How We Use Your Information 

We use the personal information you submit to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service. 

Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service (including your location information and User Content) becomes available to the public. Gowalla is not responsible for the personally identifiable, profile, or location information that you choose to disclose publicly on the Service. If you remove information that you posted to the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information. 

When you have the Gowalla Software running on your mobile phone, Gowalla shows your phone’s current geo-location to your selected Gowalla friends, as controlled by your privacy settings. 

By providing Gowalla your email address, you consent to our using the email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. We may also use your email address or mobile phone number to send you other messages, such as newsletters, changes to features of the Service, or special offers. If you do not want to receive such messages, you may opt out or change your preferences in your settings page (click Edit Profile on your Passport). Opting out may prevent you from receiving messages regarding updates, improvements, or offers. You may not opt out of Service-related e-mails. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages and our responses. 

If you choose to use our invitation service to invite a friend to the Service, we will ask you for that person’s email address and automatically send an email invitation. Gowalla stores this information to send this email, to register your friend if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our invitation service. Your friend may contact us to request that we remove this information from our database at terms@gowalla.com. 

Gowalla may use certain information about you and/or your User Content without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as analyzing how the Service is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing content. 

Gowalla reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor the User Content you post on the site. We reserve the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation if in our sole opinion such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or our Terms of Use Agreement, or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party. Gowalla also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party. 

We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our Service; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and traffic; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems reported by our users or engineers that are associated with certain IP addresses; and (f) help you efficiently access your information after you sign in. 

**Personally Identifiable Information:** Gowalla may share your personally identifiable information with third parties solely for the purpose of providing services to you. If we do this, such third parties’ use of your information will be bound by this Privacy Policy. We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of Gowalla (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). 

Gowalla does not share your personally identifiable information or personally-identifiable location information with other, third-party companies for their commercial or marketing use without your express consent or unless you have opted-in to be part of a specific program or feature. We cannot control third parties’ use of your information. If you do not want your information to be collected by or shared with such a third party, you can choose not to participate in such programs or features. As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution. 

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, Gowalla will not disclose personal information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law, comply with legal process served on us or our affiliates, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities; (b) to enforce our Terms of Use, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; and (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Gowalla, our Users or others. 

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain Gowalla services. 

Gowalla may allow third-party ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Gowalla site. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on Gowalla. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content. Gowalla does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. However, please note that if an advertiser asks Gowalla to show an advertisement to a certain audience and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. The Gowalla Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, third-party advertisers. Please consult the respective privacy policies of such advertisers for more information. 

##  How We Protect Your Information 

Gowalla uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Gowalla and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, Gowalla makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. 

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from Gowalla, at all times. 

##  Compromise of Personal Information 

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, Gowalla will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law. 

##  Your Choices About Your Information 

You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through the Service, in which case Gowalla may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may update or correct your account information [and email preferences] at any time by logging in to your account. You can review and correct the information about you that Gowalla keeps on file by contacting us directly at terms [at] Gowalla.com. 

Currently your passport has two privacy settings. **By default, Passport Privacy is off** , and others may view the Stamps in your Gowalla Passport. They may also view the Items you have collected, which include a history of the day and location where you picked up the Item. 

**If you choose to turn Passport Privacy on,** your stamps (the places you’ve been) and your items will only be visible to your friends. 

There are **three exceptions** to this rule. It’s important to understand them: 

  1. **If you create a new spot in Gowalla** , your name will be added to that spot as the creator. Don’t create a new spot if you do not want your name associated with it. 
  2. **If you drop an item at a spot** , your name will be associated with the dropped item as well as the spot where you dropped it. Do not drop an item from your pack unless you want others to know that you were at that spot. 
  3. **If you take a photo at a spot** , your photo will be associated with that Spot. All pictures are public and will remain at the Spot at which you took them. Don’t take photos at Spots unless you want others to know that you were there. 

##  Children’s Privacy 

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Gowalla does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register as Members. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to or on Gowalla. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at terms [at] Gowalla.com. 

##  Links to Other Web Sites 

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our website, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website’s own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding. 

##  Notification Procedures 

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on our website, as determined by Gowalla in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy. 

##  Changes to Our Privacy Policy 

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our website to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please contact us at live@gowalla.com, or send mail to: 

Gowalla, Inc.  
610 W 5th St.  
Suite 604  
Austin, TX 78701  
(817) 428-4248  
live@gowalla.com
